Thomas Stirling

Software Engineer

Website

tmstrlng.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/thomasdstirling

Email

tomstirling19@gmail.com

Mobile

07708 369014

GitHub

github.com/tomstirling19

GitLab

gitlab.com/tomstirling

Interests

ΑI

Web3

Blockchain

Art

Sketching

Tennis

Music

Film

Summary

Experienced software engineer with contributions to Space & Defence, Medical, Security and entertainment projects. Proven to be adept and have a strong proficiency in learning and adapting, with a goal to progress in technical software engineering.

Experience

Sky Betting and Gaming

Software Engineer, REP (Real-time events processing) - (August 2023 – Present)

- Helped create a Horse Racing Meta-data application which efficiently consumes, transforms, enriches, and publishes real-time horse racing meta-data for consumers.
 Implementing a high-performance message stream, utilising Kafka as a message store and incorporating a hash store for efficient update checks (Kotlin, Kafka, Spring boot).
- Maintain real-time event processing applications within the REP stack.

Ascent

Junior Software Engineer - (August 2022 – July 2023)

- Contributed as a full-stack engineer to a G4S client project, developing a security system to manage identities and building access, in an international environment.
 Played a key role in feature development of multiple modules (Identities, Alarms and Core), providing the primary functionality (C#, .NET).
- Contributed to the successful completion of the G4S project by passing a UAT phase, interacting with G4S in order to refine and adjust the application. Developed strong skills in client interaction and Microsoft tech-stack development.

Airbus Defence & Space

Graduate Software & Data Engineer, Ocean - (September 2021 – August 2022)

- Contributed as a full-stack engineer, towards an internal, international Airbus web application used for storing and manipulating space equipment and mission data.
 Specifically, contributing to the front-end development and also back-end functionality for data processing (Angular 13 & Java 11).
- Completed an internal project, primarily contributing towards hardware development of a prototype 'Rover', inc. self-developed front-end application (Python, Node.Js & Vue.Js).
- Contributed towards an R&D project, exploring a range of methods for visualising and manipulating dataset dependencies, within vast project datasets. Primarily integrating Angular visualisation libraries into the project's web application.

Bytemark Hosting

Junior Software Developer - (July 2018 – July 2019)

 Contributed as a full-stack engineer, developing and testing features for a cloud server management application and the Bytemark CLI client (Ruby, Go, AngularJs).

Vans

Sales Assistant - (March 2015 - August 2016)

Education

University of Leeds (September 2016 – July 2021)

MEng & BSc Computer Science, 1st class honours.

- MEng Contributed greatly towards a medical image analysis application, in partnership with the NHS. The project utilised a multi-model neural network to first segment X-ray images of wrists, labelling each bone. Furthermore, it utilised the segmented image to detect and locate fractures within the X-ray, outputting a heatmap and report containing the fractured bone and the type of fracture.
- BSc Created an autonomous robot assistant through robotics and computer vision knowledge, navigating a user to a specific and precise position within a mapped environment. It also featured facial recognition based authentication and object detection based goal determination.
- Contributed towards a mobile application, logging and rating users 'seen' and 'want to see' films through Android studio.

Modules (including but not limited to):

- Artificial intelligence & Machine learning
- Robotics and Computer vision
- Data Science
- Parallel computation

- User interfaces
- o Big data systems
- o Algorithms I & II
- o Mobile application development

o Go

Complete module transcript available upon request.

Selby College (September 2014 – July 2016)

BTEC 90 Credit Extended Diploma: IT - D*D*D* (Equivalent to A*A*A*).

Skills

Programming Languages:

JavaKotlin

PythonC#TypeScript

Frameworks and Libraries:

Angular 12+
Spring boot
PyTorch
React
Net 5+
OpenCV

Node.Js
TensorFlow & Keras

Tools and Other:

Git, Docker, AWS, Spring boot, Kafka, Jenkins, Machine Learning, Al, REST, Azure, Mongo, SQL.

Employer and academic references available upon request.